<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?><metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>AL Reefs Score</title>
        <edition>Version 1</edition>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The purpose of this dataset is to depict locations most appropriate for oyster restoration. Oysters are likely to be successful in areas where they historically have been productive. However, it is important to note that conditions may have changed in the given time span such that restoration may not be suitable in all of the areas identified by this layer. To identify areas where oysters have been or are currently found, multiple current and historic oyster reef data sets were collated and merged. Areas with reef were scored 1 and all remaining areas were scored a 0. The scored polygons were converted to a 10m, 10m grid. Original data source: Alabama Dept of Conservation, Marine Resources Division (1968, 1995), General chart of the coast (1882) (polygon), Resolution: varies from 1:24,000 to 1:200,000.</abstract>
      <purpose>In response to the Deepwater Horizon oil spill in April 2010, The Nature Conservancy in collaboration with multiple partners including NOAA, the University of Southern Mississippi, Stanford University, and ESRI, has developed an online web mapping application and robust Gulf of Mexico spatial database to help facilitate restoration and recovery decisions.  Primarily targeted to help our state programs and the state agencies and partners they work with, the Gulf Restoration Decision Support project is being advanced to inform the identification of oyster reef restoration projects with maximum ecological, social and economic benefits.  The Oyster Restoration Dashboard allows users to explore this database to identify potential restoration investments within each of the Gulf states of Florida, Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana and Texas.  


The Oyster Restoration Dashboard is organized by state and permits users to easily visualize locations most appropriate for oyster restoration investment using a suite of ecological, social and economic criteria.   The suitability criteria vary somewhat between states due to differences in data availability, however all states include basic ecological measures such as depth, salinity and historic oyster distribution. </purpose>
    </descript>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.510361</westbc>
        <eastbc>-87.688941</eastbc>
        <northbc>30.980476</northbc>
        <southbc>30.143540</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Gulf of Mexico, Oyster Restoration</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Gulf of Mexico, Florida, Mississippi, Alabama, Louisiana, Texas</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>The Nature Conservancy</cntorg>
          <cntper>Zach Ferdana</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Senior Marine Conservation Planner</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Unknown</addrtype>
          <address>1917 1st Ave </address>
          <city>Seattle</city>
          <state>WA</state>
          <postal>98101</postal>
          <country>U.S.</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>206-343-4345</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>zferdana@tnc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
      <browsen>Gulf Restoration Decision Support project</browsen>
    </browse>
    <datacred>TNC created the scored raster layers for inclusion in the Oyster Restoration Dashboard.  For more information about TNC's Gulf Restoration Decision Support project go to http://coastalresilience.org/gulf-of-mexico. </datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.2.3200</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>User Defined Mercator</mapprojn>
          <mercator>
            <stdparll>0.0</stdparll>
            <longcm>0.0</longcm>
            <feast>0.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </mercator>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000006714873101998366</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000006714873101998366</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D User Defined</horizdn>
        <ellips>User Defined Spheroid</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>0.0</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>VAT_reefs_clean</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VALUE</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20110807</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>The Nature Conservancy</cntorg>
          <cntper>Zach Ferdana</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Senior Marine Conservation Planner</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>Unknown</addrtype>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntemail>zferdana@tnc.org</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>