<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><title>Oyster Reef Restoration Suitability Scenario</title><geoform>raster digital data</geoform></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>The Gulf Restoration Decision Support project is being advanced to inform the identification of restoration projects with maximum socio-economic and ecological benefits. A coalition of partners including The Nature Conservancy, NOAA, ESRI, the University of Southern Mississippi, the Natural Capital Project, and others is providing decision support by developing an interactive web-based mapping application (http://GulfRestorationDS.org)to consolidate information about the ecological and socio-economic characteristics of the Gulf Coast and to help in defining the best restoration needs and opportunities. This process involves four key steps: 1) identifying ecological criteria that define where restoration can be successful, 2) identifying socio-economic criteria that determine when restoration is most feasible and beneficial 3) collecting, processing and analyzing spatial data that represent those criteria, and 4) delivering that information across the Web in a user-friendly mapping application. Gulf Restoration Decision Support will help decision makers to explore alternative restoration scenarios that account for these social, economic, and ecological benefits. We are also including scenarios to help understand likely future conditions from climate change and sea level rise around the Gulf of Mexico. When a user interacts with the Oyster Reef Restoration dashboard for a particular state they have the ability to assign a number of weights to various parameters. These weights are assigned through the interface by sliding a slider bar to assign a value between 0 and 10. When the user assigns a value in this manner the predefined values in each parameter are then multiplied by the weight assigned to it. These are then combined to produce an overall score of restoration suitability. When the user exports a scenario the weights displayed on the web mapping application will be captured in the attirbutes of the dataset.</abstract><purpose>The purpose of this dataset is to provide coastal managers and planners with user-driven oyster reef restoration suitability scenarios for examination in the Gulf of Mexico. These are dervied from a combination of social, economic and ecological parameters that influence the restoration of oyster reefs in each of the five Gulf states. </purpose></descript><spdom><bounding><westbc>-95.079482</westbc><eastbc>-78.245046</eastbc><northbc>34.051240</northbc><southbc>19.174941</southbc></bounding></spdom><datacred>The development of the Oyster Reef Restoration dashboards was done through a collaboration between The Nature Conservancy and the Univesity of Southern Mississippi. For more information about TNC's Gulf Restoration Decision Support project go to http://coastalresilience.org/gulf-of-mexico.</datacred><native>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7600) ; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.0.2414</native></idinfo><spdoinfo><direct>Raster</direct><rastinfo><rasttype>Pixel</rasttype><rowcount>52296</rowcount><colcount>49344</colcount></rastinfo><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="AL_scenario1"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">4</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">355</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.0000000037055025714494162</absres><ordres>0.0000000037055025714494162</ordres></coordrep><plandu>Meter</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn><ellips>GRS 1980</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222101</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed xmlns="" Name="AL_scenario1"><enttyp><enttypl>output.shp</enttypl><enttypd>When a user exports a scenario from the oyster restoration dashboard, the values that are present in the table are: 1) The products of the weight and parameter values in fields named for each parameter.  These are the values that are summed to create the score.  There are n number of these fields. 2) The score value in a field called “Score.” 3) The rescaled (0-100) score value in the field called “Dash_Score”</enttypd><enttypds>USM</enttypds><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">355</enttypc></enttyp><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Depth_Scor</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Depth_Scor</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Depth_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined depth score value.  The predefined depth score values were defined to limit the depth of placement  to a maximum of 10 feet.  All areas 10ft deep or less were scored 1 with remaining areas scored 0.  The scored raster was resampled to a 10, 10m grid.  Original data source: Kim C-K, Park K, Powers SP, Graham WM, Bayha KM (2010) Oyster larval transport in coastal Alabama: Dominance of physical transport over biological behavior in a shallow estuary. J Geophys Res 115: C10019 (raster), Resolution: 30m, 30m grid cell.  </attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Historic_R</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Historic_R</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Historic_Reefs_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined historic reef score value.  The predefined historic reef score values were defined to identify areas where oysters have been or are currently found.  Areas with reef were scored 1 and all remaining areas were scored a 0.  The scored polygons were converted to a 10m, 10m grid. Original data source: Alabama Dept of Conservation, Marine Resources Division (1968, 1995), General chart of the coast (1882) (polygon), Resolution: varies from 1:24,000 to 1:200,000.    d.  d </attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Spat_Settl</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Spat_Settl</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Spat_Settlement_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined spat settlement score value.  The predefined spat settlement score values were defined to identify areas where natural spat settlement occurs.  Larval transport studies are helpful for identifying locations most suitable for reef placement and we were provided with gridded field data characterizing patterns of spat settlement in Mobile Bay.  The original grid was reclassed into quartiles in which the top 25% of grid cells (those with the highest spat settlement) received a score of 1.  The remaining quartiles were scored .75, .5, and .25 with a score of .25 being assigned to those areas with the lowest spat settlement.  The scored grid was resampled to a 10m, 10m grid.  Original data source: Kim C-K, Park K, Powers SP, Graham WM, Bayha KM (2010) Oyster larval transport in coastal Alabama: Dominance of physical transport over biological behavior in a shallow estuary. J Geophys Res 115: C10019 (raster), Resolution: 100m, 100m grid cell.</attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Nat__Resou</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Nat__Resou</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Natural_Resources_Job_Dependence_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined natural resources job dependence score value.  The predefined natural resources job dependence score values were defined to identify areas where oyster restoration projects can provide social and economic benefits to those communities whose livelihoods depend most upon the health of coastal natural resources.  To identify coastal communities with high levels of natural resource job dependence, we used census data to map the percentage of the workforce employed in agriculture, forestry, and fishing per census block group.  Nearshore areas (within 2km of shore) adjacent to block groups with high concentrations of workers employed in natural resource dependent sectors were scored 1 while areas adjacent to medium concentrations received a score of 0.5.  All remaining areas were scored 0.  Scored polygons were converted to a 10m, 10m grid.  Original data source: 2000 US Census (polygon), Resolution: 1:100,000.</attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Project_Pe</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Project_Pe</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Project_Permit_Feasibility_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined project permit feasibility score value.  The predefined project permit feasibility score values were defined to identify areas where permitting for oyster restoration is viewed as more feasible.  In Alabama, permitting for oyster restoration is generally viewed as more feasible when reefs are placed adjacent to state or federally managed lands (public) rather than in front of privately owned land.  Nearshore areas (within 2km of shore) adjacent to public lands were scored 1 with areas adjacent to privately owned lands receiving a score of 0.  Scored polygons were converted to a 10m, 10m grid. Original data source: AL Gap Analysis Project (polygon), Resolution: 1:24,000.   </attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shoreline_</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shoreline_</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Shoreline_Erosion_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined shoreline erosion score value.  The predefined shoreline erosions score values were defined to identify areas where oyster reefs can be placed adjacent to eroding shorelines to help attenuate waves and stabilize shorelines.  To identify portions of the shoreline that are currently vulnerable to erosion, we used a portion of the USGS Coastal Vulnerability Index.  We extracted shoreline erosion rates for Alabama and reclassified the values into quartiles with scores of .25, .5, .75, and 1.  A score of 1 indicates areas with the highest erosion rates and a score of .25 indicates areas of low erosion or accretion.  The scores were then allocated to the nearshore areas (within 2km of shore) adjacent to the shoreline.  All remaining areas were scored 0.  Scored polygons were converted to a 10m, 10m grid.   Original data source: USGS Coastal Vulnerability Index (Used erosion raw values, polyline), Resolution: 3 arc-minute grid cell.</attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Salinity_S</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Salinity_S</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef>The Salinity_Score field is the the product of the weight and the predefined salinity score value.  The predefined salinity score values were defined to identify areas within optimal salinity zones (5-25ppt).   These areas were scored as most suitable for oyster restoration while areas of extreme low and high salinities were scored as least suitable.  Polygons representing optimal salinities between 5-25 ppt were scored 1 with remaining areas scored 0.  The scored polygons were converted to a 10m, 10m grid.  Original data source: Salinity Zones in Estuaries along the Gulf of Mexico- NOAA/NCDDC (polygon), Resolution: 1:24,000.    </attrdef></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl>Score</attrlabl><attalias>Score</attalias><attrdef>The score is the raw sum of the user-defined weighted parameters. </attrdef><attrdefs>USM</attrdefs><attrtype>Double</attrtype><attwidth>19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape_Leng</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_Leng</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape_Area</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_Area</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr xmlns=""><attrlabl>Dash_score</attrlabl><attalias>Dash_score</attalias><attrdef>The Dash_Score is what is displayed to the user on the map, however the raw score cannot be displayed directly because the cartography depends on the scores always maintaining a constant range.  In this case the values are rescaled to a range of 0 – 100.  Values in the range from 0 – 20 are assigned “Low”, 40 – 60 “Medium, 80 – 100 “High” and then assigned a color for display.  Values from 20 – 40 are assigned a color between the Low and Medium classes, and values from 60 – 80 a color between the Medium and High classes.  The “others” class has no meaning here as no regions will ever fall into this range. </attrdef><attrdefs>USM</attrdefs><attrtype>Integer</attrtype><attwidth>9</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">9</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed></eainfo><metainfo><metd>20110616</metd><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv></metainfo><dataIdInfo><idPurp>The purpose of this dataset is to provide coastal managers and planners with user-driven oyster reef restoration suitability scenarios for examination in the Gulf of Mexico. These are dervied from a combination of social, economic and ecological parameters that influence the restoration of oyster reefs in each of the five Gulf states. </idPurp><idCredit>The development of the Oyster Reef Restoration dashboards was done through a collaboration between The Nature Conservancy and the Univesity of Southern Mississippi. For more information about TNC's Gulf Restoration Decision Support project go to http://coastalresilience.org/gulf-of-mexico.</idCredit><idCitation xmlns=""><resTitle>Oyster Reef Restoration Suitability Scenario</resTitle><resAltTitle>Gulf Restoration Decision Support</resAltTitle><collTitle>Coastal Resilience Gulf of Mexico</collTitle><citRespParty xmlns=""><rpIndName>Zach Ferdana</rpIndName><rpOrgName>The Nature Conservancy</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Senior Marine Conservation Planner</rpPosName><rpCntInfo xmlns=""><cntAddress><eMailAdd>zferdana@tnc.org</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntOnlineRes xmlns=""><linkage>http://coastalresilience.org/gulf-of-mexico</linkage><orName>Coastal Resilience Gulf of Mexico</orName><orFunct><OnFunctCd value="002"/></orFunct></cntOnlineRes></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P STYLE="margin:0 0 14 0;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Gulf Restoration Decision Support project is being advanced to inform the identification of restoration projects with maximum socio-economic and ecological benefits. A coalition of partners including The Nature Conservancy, NOAA, ESRI, the University of Southern Mississippi, the Natural Capital Project, and others is providing decision support by developing an interactive web-based mapping application (&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;A href="http://GulfRestorationDS.org"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;http://GulfRestorationDS.org&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;)to consolidate information about the ecological and socio-economic characteristics of the Gulf Coast and to help in defining the best restoration needs and opportunities. This process involves four key steps: 1) identifying ecological criteria that define where restoration can be successful, 2) identifying socio-economic criteria that determine when restoration is most feasible and beneficial 3) collecting, processing and analyzing spatial data that represent those criteria, and 4) delivering that information across the Web in a user-friendly mapping application. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P STYLE="margin:0 0 14 0;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Gulf Restoration Decision Support will help decision makers to explore alternative restoration scenarios that account for these social, economic, and ecological benefits. We are also including scenarios to help understand likely future conditions from climate change and sea level rise around the Gulf of Mexico. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;When a user interacts with the Oyster Reef Restoration dashboard for a particular state they have the ability to assign a number of weights to various parameters. These weights are assigned through the interface by sliding a slider bar to assign a value between 0 and 10. When the user assigns a value in this manner the predefined values in each parameter are then multiplied by the weight assigned to it. These are then combined to produce an overall score of restoration suitability. When the user exports a scenario the weights displayed on the web mapping application will be captured in the attirbutes of the dataset.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><searchKeys><keyword>oyster reefs</keyword><keyword>restoration</keyword><keyword>suitability</keyword><keyword>scenarios</keyword></searchKeys><resConst xmlns=""><Consts xmlns=""><useLimit>The exported scenarios are for examination purposes only. They are intended to guide coastal managers and planners to consider oyster reef restoration in particularly geographies within the Gulf of Mexico. Through a peer and expert review process the suitability scores for soical, economic and ecological parameters were carefully assigned. However, we recognize there are other methods for determining oyster reef restoration suitability and therefore these output should be considered tentative pending a more thorough examination of on-the-ground site conditions.</useLimit></Consts></resConst><dataChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></dataChar><idPoC xmlns=""><rpIndName>Zach Ferdana</rpIndName><rpOrgName>The Nature Conservancy</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Senior Marine Conservation Planner</rpPosName><rpCntInfo xmlns=""><cntAddress><eMailAdd>zferdana@tnc.org</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntOnlineRes xmlns=""><linkage>http://gulfmex.coastalresilience.org</linkage></cntOnlineRes></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></idPoC><resMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="001"/></maintFreq><maintScp><ScopeCd value="005"/></maintScp></resMaint><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.2.3200</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="eng" country="USA"/><countryCode value="eng"/></dataLang><descKeys><thesaName uuidref="723f6998-058e-11dc-8314-0800200c9a66"/><keyword Sync="TRUE">002</keyword></descKeys><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001"/></spatRpType><dataExt xmlns=""><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-88.325710</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-87.712455</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">30.875021</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">30.223561</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="007"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="014"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="015"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><Esri><ArcGISProfile>FGDC</ArcGISProfile><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><DataProperties><lineage><Process export="False" Name="" ToolSource=""/></lineage><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">AL_scenario1</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">-9832373.073900</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-9764105.813200</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">3532318.991800</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">3616528.794000</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox><itemSize Sync="TRUE">0.998</itemSize><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\MAPS21\C$\arcgisserver\data\Gulf of Mexico\chris\AL_exports\to_ZF\AL_scenario1.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984_Major_Auxiliary_Sphere</geogcsn><projcsn Sync="TRUE">WGS_1984_Web_Mercator</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.0'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;WGS_1984_Web_Mercator&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_WGS_1984_Major_Auxiliary_Sphere&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_WGS_1984_Major_Auxiliary_Sphere&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;WGS_1984_Major_Auxiliary_Sphere&amp;quot;,6378137.0,0.0]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Mercator&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Standard_Parallel_1&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;ESRI&amp;quot;,102113]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-20037700&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-30241100&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;148923141.92838538&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;102113&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><copyHistory><copy source="C:\arcgisserver\data\Gulf of Mexico\chris\AL_exports\Mixed_output2\scenario1" dest="\\MAPS21\C$\arcgisserver\data\Gulf of Mexico\chris\AL_exports\to_ZF\scenario1" date="20110727" time="12564300"/></copyHistory></DataProperties><SyncDate>20110727</SyncDate><SyncTime>14352700</SyncTime><ModDate>20110727</ModDate><ModTime>14352700</ModTime><MapLyrSync>TRUE</MapLyrSync></Esri><mdFileID>Oyster Reef Restoration Suitability</mdFileID><mdParentID>Gulf Restoration Decision Support</mdParentID><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="US"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><mdContact xmlns=""><rpIndName>Zach Ferdana</rpIndName><rpOrgName>The Nature Conservancy</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Senior Marine Conservation Planner</rpPosName><rpCntInfo xmlns=""><cntAddress><eMailAdd>zferdana@tnc.og</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntOnlineRes xmlns=""><linkage>http://gulfmex.coastalresilience.org</linkage><orDesc>Gulf Restoration Decision Support</orDesc></cntOnlineRes></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></mdContact><mdMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="001"/></maintFreq><maintScp><ScopeCd value="005"/></maintScp></mdMaint><mdConst xmlns=""><Consts><useLimit>The exported scenarios are for examination purposes only. They are intended to guide coastal managers and planners to consider oyster reef restoration in particularly geographies within the Gulf of Mexico. Through a peer and expert review process the suitability scores for soical, economic and ecological parameters were carefully assigned. However, we recognize there are other methods for determining oyster reef restoration suitability and therefore these output should be considered tentative pending a more thorough examination of on-the-ground site conditions.</useLimit></Consts></mdConst><dqInfo xmlns=""><dqScope><scpLvl><ScopeCd value="005"/></scpLvl></dqScope></dqInfo><distInfo xmlns=""><distFormat xmlns=""><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distFormat><distTranOps xmlns=""><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.998</transSize></distTranOps></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID xmlns=""><identCode code="102113"/><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">ESRI</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">10.0.0</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001"/></topLvl><geometObjs><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002"/><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">355</geoObjCnt></geoObjTyp></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110727</mdDateSt><contInfo><FetCatDesc xmlns=""><compCode>False</compCode><incWithDS>False</incWithDS></FetCatDesc></contInfo></metadata>
