<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>All Potential Advancement Zones of Irregularly Flooded Marsh in Grand Bay, Mississippi from 2025 to 2100, derived from predicted landcover maps produced by the Sea Level Rise Affecting Marsh Model (SLAMM) using the 1m of Sea Level Rise by 2100 Scenario</title>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This file shows all potential advancement zones of irregularly flooded marsh for the Grand Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve (NERR) from 2025 to 2100. The file was derived from the predicted landcover maps of 2025, 2050, 2075, and 2100 produced by the Sea Level Rise Affecting Marsh Model (SLAMM) using the 1m of sea level rise by 2100 scenario. The file was created by extracting all of the pixels representing areas of gains of irrregularly flooded marsh in the 2025, 2050, 2075, and 2100 predicted landcover maps as compared to the intial condition in 2009. These areas of gains for all years were combined into one category to represent all future potential advancement zones of irregularly flooded marsh with 1m of sea level rise by 2100. The locations of irregularly flooded marshes in 2009 were included as a second cateogry to show where the marshes would advance from.</abstract>
      <purpose>Tidal marshes are among the most susceptible ecosystems to climate change, especially accelerated sea-level rise (SLR).  The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) Special Report on Emissions Scenarios (SRES) suggested that global sea level will increase by approximately 30 cm to 100 cm by 2100 (IPCC 2001).  Rahmstorf (2007) suggests that this range may be too conservative and that the feasible range by 2100 is 50 to 140 cm.  Rising sea levels may result in tidal marsh submergence (Moorhead and Brinson 1995) and habitat “migration” as salt marshes transgress landward and replace tidal freshwater and irregularly-flooded marsh (R. A. Park et al. 1991).  

Beginning in 2009, the Nature Conservancy and Warren Pinnacle Consulting, Inc. worked together to produce an analysis of the potential effects of sea-level rise on Grand Bay Estuary and its environs.  Funding for TNC was provided through a grant from the Gulf of Mexico Foundation to support the Habitat Conservation &amp; Restoration Team, a part of the Governor’s Gulf of Mexico Alliance. </purpose>
    </descript>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-88.499212</westbc>
        <eastbc>-88.265919</eastbc>
        <northbc>30.485571</northbc>
        <southbc>30.313640</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>SLAMM</themekey>
        <themekey>Sea Level Rise</themekey>
        <themekey>SLR</themekey>
        <themekey>Grand Bay</themekey>
        <themekey>Mississippi</themekey>
        <themekey>NERR</themekey>
        <themekey>Marsh,</themekey>
        <themekey>Migration,</themekey>
        <themekey>Advancement Zone</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The user accepts all responsibility for use of these data.</useconst>
    <native>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.2.3200</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Pixel</rasttype>
      <rowcount>2219</rowcount>
      <colcount>2597</colcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 Web Mercator Auxiliary Sphere</mapprojn>
          <mapprojp>
            <otherprj>PROJCS["WGS_1984_Web_Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere",GEOGCS["GCS_WGS_1984",DATUM["D_WGS_1984",SPHEROID["WGS_1984",6378137.0,298.257223563]],PRIMEM["Greenwich",0.0],UNIT["Degree",0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION["Mercator_Auxiliary_Sphere"],PARAMETER["False_Easting",0.0],PARAMETER["False_Northing",0.0],PARAMETER["Central_Meridian",0.0],PARAMETER["Standard_Parallel_1",0.0],PARAMETER["Auxiliary_Sphere_Type",0.0],UNIT["Meter",1.0],AUTHORITY["EPSG",3857]]-20037700-30241100148923141.92838538-10000010000-100000100000.0010.0010.001true3857</otherprj>
          </mapprojp>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000006714873101998366</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000006714873101998366</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>irreg_advzn.vat</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Rowid</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VALUE</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNT</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20111101</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>