<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>2009 Public Oyster Seed Ground Rehabilitation (Cultch Plantings) LDWF</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>2009 Public Ground Rehabilitation ActivitiesBlack Bay Cultch Plant (Plaquemines Parish)Project dates: May 16 - 31, 2009 Project location: East Lonesome Island Project size: Approximately 200 acres Material utilized: Size #57 crushed limestone rock and crushed concrete (approx. 1.5? across widest diameter) Amount of material planted: approximately 22,500.00 cubic yards (~29,300 tons) Contractor: Pontchartrain Materials Corporation (New Orleans, LA) Project cost: $1,350,759.06 Planting methods: High-pressure water spray and clam bucket utilized to spread a thin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: 36 barge-loads of limestone, 4 tug boats, 1 spray/crane barge, 1 quarter barge (to house 10 contractor employees on-site) Typical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 4 barge-loads by 6:30 p.m.Sister Lake (Caillou) Cultch Plant (Terrebonne Parish)Project dates: May 3 - 12, 2009 Project location: Sister (Caillou) Lake Project size: Approximately 170 acres Material utilized: Size #57 crushed limestone rock and crushed concrete (approx. 1.5? across widest diameter) Amount of material planted: approximately 22,597 cubic yards (~29,376 tons) Contractor: Pontchartrain Materials Corporation (New Orleans, LA) Project cost: $1,677,618.36 Planting methods: High-pressure water spray and clam bucket utilized to spread a thin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: barge-loads of cultch material, 4 tug boats, 1 spray/crane barge Typical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 3-6 barge-loads by 5:30 p.m. Lake Chien Cultch Plant (Terrebonne Parish)Project dates: May 4 - June 10, 2009 Project location: Lake Chien Project size: approximately 22 acres Material utilized: Size #57 limestone rock (approx. 1.5? across widest diameter) Amount of material planted: approximately 11,348 cubic yards (~ 15,320 tons) Contractor: Bertucci Contracting Co., LLC Project cost: $828,413.49 Planting methods: Clam bucket utilized to spread a thin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: 13 barge-loads of limestone, 2 tug boats, 1 quarter barge (to house 6 contractor employees on-site) Typical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 2 barge-loads by 6:30 p.m.Mississippi Sound Cultch Plant (St. Bernard Parish)Project dates: May 4 - June 11, 2009 Project location: Three Mile Bay Project size: approximately 45 acres Material utilized: Size #57 limestone rock (approx. 1.5? across widest diameter) Amount of material planted: approximately 22,300 cubic yards (29,150tons) Contractor: Bertucci Contracting Co., LLC Project cost: $1,372,224.29 Planting methods: Clam bucket utilized to spread a thin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: barge-loads of limestone, 2 tug boats, 1 quarter barge (to house 6 contractor employees on-site) Typical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 2 barge-loads by 6:30 p.m. *Note: a 15-acre cultch plant in southern Calcasieu Lake was also constructed in 2009, but was funded by state compensation monies.2008 Public Ground Rehabilitation ActivitiesHackberry Bay Cultch Plant (Lafourche/Jefferson Parish)Project dates: May 20 - 25, 2008 Project location: Hackberry Bay Project size: Approximately 50 acres Material utilized: Approximately 75% Size #57 limestone rock, approximately 15% crushed concrete, and approximately 10% clean oyster shells Amount of material planted: 10,171.75 cubic yards (~ 13,223 tons) Contractor: Pontchartrain Materials Corporation (New Orleans, LA) Project cost: $558,429.00 Planting methods: High-pressure water spray and clam bucket utilized to spread a thin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: 11 barge-loads of cultch material, 3 tug boats, 1 spray/crane bargeTypical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 3-4 barge-loads by 6:30 p.m.2007 Public Ground Rehabilitation ActivitiesBlack Bay Cultch Plant (Plaquemines Parish)Project dates: May 8-19, 2007 Project location: Northeast of Lonesome Island (sunken marsh island) Project size: Approximately 200 acres Material utilized: Size #57 limestone rock (approx. 1.5" across widest diameter)Amount of material planted: 32,235 cubic yards (~ 41,905 tons) Contractor: Pontchartrain Materials Corporation (New Orleans, LA) Project cost: $1,725,830 Planting methods: High-pressure water spray and clam bucket utilized to spread a thin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: 36 barge-loads of limestone, 4 tug boats, 1 spray/crane barge, 1 quarter barge (to house 10 contractor employees on-site) Typical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 4 barge-loads by 6:30 p.m.Mississippi Sound Cultch Plant (St. Bernard Parish)Project dates: June 4 - June 13, 2007 Project location: Northwest of Turkey Bayou, northeast of 3-Mile Pass Project size: Approximately 200 acres Material utilized: Size #57 limestone rock (approx. 1.5" across widest diameter) Amount of material planted: 30,000 cubic yards (~ 39,000 tons) Contractor: Pontchartrain Materials Corporation (New Orleans, LA) Project cost: $1,610,000 Planting methods: High-pressure water spray and clam bucket utilized to spread athin layer of cultch material on water bottoms Equipment used: : 36 barge-loads of limestone, 4 tug boats, 1 spray/crane barge, 1 quarter barge (to house 10 contractor employees on-site) Typical work day: Begin at 6:30 a.m. and unload ~ 4 barge-loads by 6:30 p.m.Projects are funded by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (grant # NA06NMF4540319) through the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission (sub-award # OR-RRR-020-2006-01) as part of the recent $53 million federal fisheries rehabilitation appropriation for Louisiana in the wakes of the 2005 hurricanes. Additional projects planned for the $53M include oyster rehabilitation on private oyster leases, debris removal on traditional fishing grounds, and cooperative research to monitor recovery of fishery resources impacted by the hurricanes of 2005.For more information, contact Patrick Banks at 225.765.2370 or pbanks@wlf.louisiana.gov.</abstract>
      <purpose>This data layer represents areas currenlty undergoing oyster reef rehabilitation.  The areas have been planted with cultch materials for oyster reef restoration purposes.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-92.142943</westbc>
        <eastbc>-91.762228</eastbc>
        <northbc>29.838347</northbc>
        <southbc>29.459331</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords />
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>N/A</useconst>
    <datacred>Louisiana Department of Fisheries and Wildlife (LDWF) 2007-2009</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.2.3200</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>63</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>NAD 1983 StatePlane Louisiana South FIPS 1702</mapprojn>
          <lambertc>
            <stdparll>29.3</stdparll>
            <stdparll>30.7</stdparll>
            <longcm>-91.33333333333333</longcm>
            <latprjo>28.5</latprjo>
            <feast>1000000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </lambertc>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000008667822015695493</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000008667822015695493</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>Meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Blank_Copy_for_Cultch_Plant_Metadata</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_Leng</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE_Area</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Area</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Hectares</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20110819</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>