<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Louisiana Oil Spill Coordinator's Office (LOSCO)</origin>
				<pubdate>1999</pubdate>
				<title>Bathymetry for Louisiana, Geographic NAD83, LOSCO (1994) [bathymetry_NOAA_1994]</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<onlink>http://lagic.lsu.edu/data/losco/bathymetry_NOAA_1994.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>
This is a line data depicting the offshore bathymetry_NOAA_1994 for Louisiana.  The contour
interval is 2 meters.  These data were derived from point depths depicted on
NOAA Navigation charts.  The depths on the NOAA charts are typically relative
to 'mean low Gulf' levels, so these depths are conservative.
</abstract>
			<purpose>
A precursor to this dataset was developed as a surface for numerical wave
modeling.  This data set was developed in order that the 10 meter depth
line could be extracted for other uses.  The 10 meter depth line forms a regulatory
boundary for dispersant use and in-situ burn pre-approval areas.

The user should be aware that meteorological events such as hurricanes
may alter these depths or may have already have already altered the actual depths
from those represented on the source NOAA charts.  Furthermore,
geomorphological processes due to sediment load are causing landward
migration of isocontours at a rate of about 25 meters per year in the
Mississippi River Delta Plain area (east and west of where the Mississippi
empties out into the Gulf).  Because these data are based on historical
NOAA charts, the effects of this migration have not been captured.
</purpose>
			<supplinf>
The metadata for this data set are encapsulated into several documents
and graphics files.  The metadata are not complete if you did not
receive the following files along in the data set:

&gt;bathymetry_NOAA_1994.mtd - this metadata in mp (metadata parser) compatible ASCII text form
&gt;bathymetry_NOAA_1994.html - this metadata in HTML form
&gt;bathymetry_NOAA_1994_faq.html - this metadata presented as Questions and Answers
&gt;bathymetry_NOAA_1994.sgml - this metadata in SGML form
&gt;bathymetry_NOAA_1994_01.gif - thumbnail graphic of data set
</supplinf>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<rngdates>
					<begdate>19900400</begdate>
					<enddate>19940600</enddate>
				</rngdates>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>Range of publication dates of NOAA charts from which depths were digitized.</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-93.951630</westbc>
				<eastbc>-88.821663</eastbc>
				<northbc>30.369144</northbc>
				<southbc>28.541408</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>none</themekt>
				<themekey>navigation charts</themekey>
				<themekey>bathymetric lines</themekey>
				<themekey>wave modeling</themekey>
				<themekey>NOAA</themekey>
				<themekey>Elevation</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>none</placekt>
				<placekey>Louisiana</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>none</accconst>
		<useconst>
These unaltered data may not be redistributed without all of the elements
of the metadata listed in the Supplemental_Information section of this
metadata document.  It is recommended that third parties wishing to use
these data obtain them from the Distributor listed in this metadata document.

If these data are altered or incorporated into another dataset, they are not
to be redistributed without also: altering the name of the dataset,
including a Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata
(FGDC-STD-001-1998) compliant metadata file that describes the dataset and
reflects the alteration steps that makes the new dataset different from this
one, and citing this dataset in the metadata as a source for the altered
dataset using the source citation specified below.

If these digital data are used in the production of a report or in the compilation of a
standalone printed map, then this dataset is to be cited in the report or on the map
using the source citation specified below.

The following source citation is to be used when citing this dataset:
LOSCO Environmental Baseline Inventory Dataset 'Louisiana Offshore bathymetry_NOAA_1994,
Geographic NAD83, LOSCO (1999) [bathymetry_NOAA_1994]'

Users hereby agree to abide by the use and reproduction conditions specified above.
By using the data described in these metadata, the user acknowledges that the terms
and conditions of use have been read and that the user is bound by these criteria.
</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Louisiana Oil Spill Coordinator's Office</cntorg>
					<cntper>David Gisclair</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Technical Assistance Program (TAP) Director</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>Louisiana Oil Spill Coordinator's Office</address>
					<address>Office of the Governor</address>
					<address>150 Third Street, Suite 405</address>
					<city>Baton Rouge</city>
					<state>LA</state>
					<postal>70801</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(225) 219-5800</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>(225) 219-5802</cntfax>
				<cntemail>&lt;URL:mailto:david.gisclair@la.gov&gt;</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<browse>
			<browsen>&lt;URL: bathymetry_NOAA_1994.gif&gt;</browsen>
			<browset>GIF</browset>
		</browse>
		<datacred>
LOSCO gratefully acknowledges the Coastal Morphology Lab, Coastal Studies
Institute at LSU for providing the source data for production of this data set.
</datacred>
		<native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.0.1324</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<logic>
Original digitized points were checked with a proximity
(anomaly) filter.  There are 17 intersection errors in the
data set, primarily where neighboring contour lines
make contact.
</logic>
		<complete>
These data represent contours that are oceanward of the the first 2 meter
depth line that runs the entire length of the Louisiana Coast.  All contours
landward of this line have been deleted.  The data set has a
gap in the region of the Chandeleur Islands.  At depths
of 1000 meters and greater, the contour interval increases
to 10 meters.
</complete>
		<lineage>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>
Bathymetric points were digitized from the NOAA (NOS) 1:80,000 navigation
charts. Intergraph design files were produced for seven charts. Intergraph
Terrain Analyst was used to produce a single file with 500 foot, interpolated
grid points in ASCII format.
</procdesc>
				<procdate>1999</procdate>
				<proccont>
					<cntinfo>
						<cntorgp>
							<cntorg>Louisiana State University, Coastal Studies Institute</cntorg>
							<cntper>Dr. Greg Stone</cntper>
						</cntorgp>
						<cntaddr>
							<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
							<address>Louisiana State University</address>
							<city>Baton Rouge</city>
							<state>LA</state>
							<postal>70803</postal>
						</cntaddr>
						<cntvoice>(225) 578-4728</cntvoice>
						<cntemail>GAGREG@lsu.edu</cntemail>
					</cntinfo>
				</proccont>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>
The ASCII formatted file was transformed into a 2 meter (contour interval)
vector file using TerraModel. Design files were exported and converted into
ArcView shapefiles.
</procdesc>
				<procdate>19990915</procdate>
				<proccont>
					<cntinfo>
						<cntorgp>
							<cntorg>3001, Inc.</cntorg>
							<cntper>Jeff Lower</cntper>
						</cntorgp>
						<cntaddr>
							<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
							<address>3655 SW 2nd Avenue, Suite 3-C</address>
							<city>Gainesville</city>
							<state>FL</state>
							<postal>32607</postal>
						</cntaddr>
						<cntvoice>(352) 379-3001</cntvoice>
						<cntemail>jlower@gnv.3001data.com</cntemail>
					</cntinfo>
				</proccont>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>
The shapefile in UTM zone 15, NAD83 coordinates was edited to remove all
contours landward of the first 2 meter depth contour that was continuous
along the entire coast of Louisiana.  The shapefile was converted to a
line Arc/Info coverage, then projected to geographic coordinates NAD83.
The arc intersect errors that were readily resolved (about half) were corrected.
The resultant cover was converted to a shape and the arcs of the shape
were merged on the depth value.
</procdesc>
				<procdate>19991027</procdate>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>518</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
		</ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geograph>
				<latres>0.000000</latres>
				<longres>0.000000</longres>
				<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
			</geograph>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>bathymetry_NOAA_1994</enttypl>
				<enttypd>point attribute table for bathymetry_NOAA_1994</enttypd>
				<enttypds>3001, Inc.</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>LEGEND</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>depth_m</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>depth that contour delineates</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>3001, Inc.</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-1180.00</rdommin>
						<rdommax>-2.00</rdommax>
						<attrunit>meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>DEPTH_M</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FIRST_CONT</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape_Leng</attrlabl>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Louisiana Oil Spill Coordinator's Office</cntorg>
					<cntper>David Gisclair</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Technical Assistance Program (TAP) Director</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>Louisiana Oil Spill Coordinator's Office</address>
					<address>Office of the Governor</address>
					<address>150 Third Street, Suite 405</address>
					<city>Baton Rouge</city>
					<state>LA</state>
					<postal>70801</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(225) 219-5800</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>(225) 219-5802</cntfax>
				<cntemail>&lt;URL:mailto:david.gisclair@la.gov&gt;</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>bathymetry_NOAA_1994</resdesc>
		<distliab>
The data herein, including but not limited to geographic
data, tabular data, analytical data, electronic data
structures or files, are provided "as is" without warranty of
any kind, either expressed or implied, or statutory,
including, but not limited to, the implied warranties or
merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose.  The
entire risk as to the quality and performance of the data is
assumed by the user.  No guarantee of accuracy is
granted, nor is any responsibility for reliance thereon
assumed.  In no event shall the Louisiana Oil Spill
Coordinator's Office (LOSCO) be liable for direct, indirect,
incidental, consequential or special damages of any kind,
including, but not limited to, loss of anticipated profits or
benefits arising out of use of or reliance on the data. The
LOSCO does not accept liability for any damages or
misrepresentation caused by inaccuracies in the data or as
a result of changes to the data caused by system transfers
or other transformations or conversions, nor is there
responsibility assumed to maintain the data in any manner
or form.

These data have been developed from the best available
sources.  Although efforts have been made to ensure that
the data are accurate and reliable, errors and variable
conditions originating from physical sources used to
develop the data may be reflected in the data supplied.
Users must be aware of these conditions and bear
responsibility for the appropriate use of the information with
respect to possible errors, scale, resolution, rectification,
positional accuracy, development methodology, time
period, environmental and climatic conditions and other
circumstances specific to these data.  The user is
responsible for understanding the accuracy limitations of
the data provided herein.  The burden for determining
fitness for use lies entirely with the user.  The user should
refer to the accompanying metadata notes for a description
of the data and data development procedures.

Although these data have been processed successfully on
computers at the LOSCO, no guarantee, expressed or
implied, is made by LOSCO regarding the use of these data
on any other system, nor does the act of distribution
constitute or imply any such warranty.  Distribution of these
data is intended for information purposes and should not be
considered authoritative for navigational, engineering, legal
and other site-specific uses.
</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>SHP and MDB</formname>
					<formspec>ESRI Shapefile and Geodatabase (9.1)</formspec>
					<transize>10.717</transize>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>http://lagic.lsu.edu/data/losco/bathymetry_NOAA_1994.zip</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
					<offoptn>
						<offmedia>DVD-ROM</offmedia>
					</offoptn>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20070821</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>3001, Inc.</cntorg>
					<cntper>Mendi Johnson</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>GIS Analyst</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>3655 SW 2nd Ave., Suite 3C</address>
					<city>Gainesville</city>
					<state>FL</state>
					<postal>32607</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(352) 379-3001</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>(352) 377-4234</cntfax>
				<cntemail>mjohnson@gnv.3001data.com</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
	</metainfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20110818</CreaDate><CreaTime>15032500</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\AR201-MJENKS\I$\DSS\LA_Suitablility_Rasters\Web_Mercator_PRJ\100m_cells\XML_Metadata\Supplemental\LA_bathymetry_noaa_1994</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="I:\DSS\For_Gulf_DSS\LA\bathymetry_NOAA_1994\LA_bathymetry_noaa_1994" dest="\\AR201-MJENKS\I$\DSS\LA_Suitablility_Rasters\Web_Mercator_PRJ\100m_cells\XML_Metadata\Supplemental\LA_bathymetry_noaa_1994" date="20110818" time="15032500"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties></Esri></metadata>
